Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records ALBA.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General Files, 1940-2006
  - Spanish Labor Alliance, undated, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Spanish Labor Alliance: Report, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc., undated, 1960-1980 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Spanish Refugee Appeal, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Spanish Refugees, undated, 1940, 1950-1958 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Spanish Refugees: Chile: Timon(publication), undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Spanish Refugees: Committee of Spanish Refugees of Chile, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Spanish Refugees: Cuba, 1947, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Spanish Refugees: France, undated, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Spanish Refugees: Ministry of Labor and Social Assistance, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Spanish Sailors, Committee to Save, undated, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Starini, Joseph: Deportation, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Steck, Bob, undated, 1996-1998 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Student Papers, 1979-1994 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Student Papers: "American and Red to the Core: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War," K. Unger (Yale), 1998 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Student Papers: "American Veterans of the Spanish Civil War," K. Jacobson. (with oral history transcripts: Clarence Forester, Martin Maki, Joe Travascio), 1996 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Student Papers: Brandeis University, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Szurek, Alexander: Autobiography, The Shattered Dream, undated, 1974, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Theater: Boyington, Mike, Dancer in Madrid(script), undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Thompson, Bob, undated, 1949-1968, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Tyler, Hamilton: The Pilgrimage of Evan Cade, I, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Tyler, Hamilton: The Pilgrimage of Evan Cade, II, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Twin Cities Cultural Workers Association, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee, undated, 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Bulletins, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Committee for the Release of International Volunteers in French and Spanish Prison Camps, undated, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Rescue Ship Mission, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1974-1978 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - United States Dept. of Justice: Foreign Agents Registration Act, Correspondence, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Van der Schelling, Bart, 1993, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Histories of, ca.1940-1984 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - VALB: Histories of, drafts, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Veterans: Rehabilitation, ca.1941 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Veterans' Rights, 1943, 1956, 1971-1985 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Vietnam War, undated, 1967-1969 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Volunteer: General, undated, 1958, 1975-1990 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Volunteer: Correspondence, undated, 1973-1990 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Volunteer: "Cracker Barrel", undated, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Volunteer: Materials, Unused, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Volunteer: Materials for Inclusion, undated, 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Websites re: International Brigades, undated, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Weinberg, Gerald, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Weissman, Irving: Botwin File, 1972-1994 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Wellman, Saul, undated, 1969-1987 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Wildegans, Gustav, 1973-1979 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, 1947, 1970-1995 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - World War II: Veterans, Civilian Defense, 1941-1943 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Zlatovski, George: An Anti Hero of Our Time, undated, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 32)
- Series III: Scrapbooks (Oversize), 1939-1953; undated
  This series consists of two scrapbooks. One scrapbook contains official correspondence dating from 1939 to 1953. It includes fundraising letters signed by Lillian Hellman, Paul Robeson, Vincent Sheean, and David McKelvy White, among others. The second scrapbook contains broadsides, invitations, tickets, stamps, and brochures for dances, rallies, fundraisers and other VALB events. These scrapbooks provide an overview of VALB’s early years.
  - Correspondence, undated, 1939-1953 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Unprocessed Material (Box 24, Box 25, Box 26)